eurocircuits.com 2012-05-02

# Privacy statement | Eurocircuits

Eurocircuits is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring you have a positive experience on our website. This  
policy outlines our personal information handling practices for both online and offline data. If you give us personal   
information, we will treat it according to this policy.

This policy covers the Eurocircuits website and is applicable worldwide. Some of our related companies or programs may  
have their own, possibly different, policies. We encourage you to read this privacy policy and those of all websites you  
visit.

## Collection of your personal information

We will always tell you before we collect any Personal Information and inform you of the purpose of the collection.  
“Personal Information” is any information that can be used to identify an individual, and may include, but is not limited to,  
name, email address, postal or other physical address, credit or debit card number, title, occupation, and other  
information required to provide a service, deliver a product, or carry out a transaction you have requested. Some of the  
reasons we collect your Personal Information include:

  * registration of an account
  * use of certain features of our products or services
  * requesting service and support for our products or services
  * placement of a transaction or order
  * registration to attend a seminar
  * participation in an online survey
  * participation in discussion groups or forum
  * collaboration efforts
  * registration to membership programs or newsletter subscriptions

## Uses of your personal information

We will only use your Personal Information in the way we specified when it was collected. We will not subsequently  
change the way your Personal Information is used without your consent. Some of the ways we may use your Personal  
Information include:

  * To process your orders and deliver the products and services that you have ordered.
  * To keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, website updates, special offers, and other  
information. This may occasionally include information from other technology companies about products and services that  
can add value to your Eurocircuits services and products.
  * To provide support and assistance for our products and services.
  * To provide the ability to create personal profile areas and view protected content.
  * To provide the ability to contact you, and provide you with shipping and billing information.
  * To provide customer feedback and support.
  * To provide marketing or promotional activities on the Eurocircuits.com website.  
Personal Information may be collected to administer those programs.
  * collected to administer those programs.
  *   * To conduct questionnaires and surveys in order to provide better products and services to our customers.   
Your completion of any questionnaires is voluntary
  *   * To understand more about you, so we can personalize newsletters and websites to your preferences. For example,  
allow you the opportunity to request specific information on products and services that may be of interest.
  *   * To allow you to forward information to another individual such as a friend or co-worker. Eurocircuits does not   
store the personal information of the third party. We collect the information for the sole purpose of sending a   
one-time email. If you choose to use our referral service to inform a colleague or friend, we will only ask for a   
contact name and email address.
  * To meet contract obligations.

## Accessing and updating your personal information.

We need your help in keeping the Personal Information you have shared with us accurate and up to date. Please notify us   
of any changes to your Personal Information.  
If you are a registered user, you may make these updates yourself online via the Eurocircuits Profile Management Tool.   
You may also make these updates or request deactivation of your Eurocircuits account by sending an email to   
[privacy@eurocircuits.com](mailto:privacy@eurocircuits.com) .

## Unsubscribing

Each email newsletter includes instructions on how you can unsubscribe from that particular mailing.  
You may also unsubscribe from Eurocircuits’ various newsletters by sending a letter, including your name, email address   
and the title of the marketing material you wish to unsubscribe from to:

Eurocircuits N.V., Antwerpesesteenweg 66, 2800 Mechelen, Belgium.

## Non-personal/anonymous information collection

In some instances, Eurocircuits may collect non-personal (aggregate or demographic) data through cookies, web logs, and  
web beacons. This information is used to better understand and improve the usability, performance, and effectiveness of  
the website. Please read the “Cookies” section below for more information.

## Sharing your personal information

We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to third parties for marketing purposes.  
We may share your Personal Information within Eurocircuits or any of our worldwide related companies for purposes of   
data processing or storage.

We may also share your Personal Information with business partners or contractors in order to provide a requested  
service or transaction, including processing orders, processing credit card transactions, hosting websites, hosting event   
and seminar registration and providing customer support. We only provide these third parties with the minimum amount   
of Personal Information necessary to complete the requested service or transaction, and the third parties are not  
permitted to use your Personal Information except for limited purpose of completing the requested service or transaction.  
We may respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process by disclosing your Personal Information and other related   
information, if necessary. We also may choose to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.  
We may collect and possibly share Personal Information and any other additional information available to us in order to   
investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to  
the physical safety of any person, violations of Eurocircuits’ terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

While navigating Eurocircuits’ web site you may be directed to content or functionality that is hosted by a third-party   
supplier, not on eurocircuits.com. This is typically done to host special events, such as contests or to organize online  
payments. When information is collected on behalf of Eurocircuits exclusively, Eurocircuits’ privacy policy will be   
referenced on the site and will govern how your information is used. For other, non-Eurocircuits sites, the site owner’s  
privacy policy will be referenced. It is Eurocircuits’ practice to require such suppliers to handle information in a manner   
consistent with Eurocircuits’ privacy and security policies.

We will ask for your consent before we use or share your information for any purpose other than the reason you provided  
it or as otherwise provided by this policy. In order to let us know your preferences, we will require an action on your part,  
such as checking the appropriate option, to indicate your consent.

## Security of your personal information

Eurocircuits is committed to protecting the Personal Information you share with us. We utilize a combination of industrystandard security technologies, procedures,   
and organizational measures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

When we transfer sensitive personal data (for example, credit card information) over the Internet, we protect it using   
Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology.  
While we strive to protect your Personal Information, we cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit.

We recommend you to take every precaution in protecting your Personal Information when you are on the Internet. For   
example, change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers when creating passwords, and make  
sure you use a secure browser. Please visit the Linksys website for more tips for using security features when connected   
to the Internet using a router.

## Cookies

Like many websites, Eurocircuits uses technologies, such as cookies and web beacons, which allow us to make your visit   
to our website easier, more efficient and more valuable by providing you with a customized experience and recognizing   
you when you return.

A cookie cannot read personal data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites; indeed, the only Personal   
Information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. Accepting the cookies used on our website may give  
us access to information about your browsing behavior, which we may use to personalize your experience and track user   
traffic patterns, and to merge this info when you register. We do this in order to determine the usefulness of our website   
information to our users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information. You  
may browse most of Eurocircuits’ website without accepting cookies from Eurocircuits; however, some website   
functionality may be lost by disabling cookies on your computer. Other Eurocircuits web pages, particularly those which   
require a login and password, require cookies and cannot be used when you have disabled cookies in your browser.  
In addition, Eurocircuits uses web beacons in conjunction with cookies to understand user behavior. Web beacons are   
simply a convenient way of gathering basic statistics and managing cookies, and do not give away any extra information   
from your computer. Turning off your browser’s cookies will prevent web beacons from tracking your specific activity.

If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our website or via HTML-formatted emails, you can set your browser to  
warn you before it accepts cookies or refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse  
all cookies by turning them off in your browser.

## Data retention

Eurocircuits will not retain your Personal Information longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was  
collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations.

## Linked websites

Our websites may provide links to other third-party websites which are outside our control and not covered by this policy.  
We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these (and all) sites you visit.

## Newsgroups/Forums/Blogs

If you participate in a Eurocircuits discussion forum or chat room or blog discussion, you should be aware that the information you provide   
there will be made broadly available to others, potentially inside or outside Eurocircuits, who have access to that   
discussion forum or chat room. Also, please recognize that individual forums and chat rooms may have additional rules  
and conditions. Each participant’s opinion on a forum or chat room is his or her own and should not be considered as   
reflecting the opinion of Eurocircuits

## Children’s privacy

Eurocircuits does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have   
collected Personal Information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that data from our systems. Eurocircuits  
encourages parents and guardians to go online with their children. Here are a few tips to help make a child’s online  
experience safer:

  *   * Teach children never to give Personal Information (such as name, address, phone number, school, etc.) unless  
supervised by a parent or responsible adult.
  * Know the sites your children are visiting and which sites are appropriate.
  * Look for website privacy policies. Know how your child’s information is treated.

Please visit the government official website for more tips on protecting children’s privacy online.

## Transfer of personal information

We may transfer your Personal Information to any Eurocircuits related company worldwide, or to third parties acting  
on our behalf for the purposes of processing orders or data storage.

## Questions or comments?

Should you have any privacy-related questions or comments related to this privacy policy, please send an email to   
[privacy@eurocircuits.com](mailto:privacy@eurocircuits.com) .

## Policy updates

Eurocircuits may amend this privacy statement from time to time, and at any time. We will post a notice whenever this   
privacy statement is materially changed. Your continued use of the Eurocircuits website after any change will signify and  
confirm your assent to those changes.
